A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Teen fathers in the inner city: an exploratory ethnographic study, 1985 Apr. (Reports 011409) (Box 474)
  Teenage parents -- New York (N.Y.); Teenage fathers -- New York (N.Y.); Unmarried fathers -- New York (N.Y.); Afro-American families -- New York (N.Y.); Youth -- New York (N.Y.); Teenage pregnancy -- New York (N.Y.); Poor -- New York (N.Y.)
- A status report of the vocational teacher education programs at the University of Nigeria, Nsukka (Reports 011410), 1971 (Box 474)
  07000023
  2 leaves, 40 p.
  Vocational teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria
- Reporte de la evaluacion de los primeros cinco anos del Plan Sierra (Reports 011411), 1984 (Box 474)
  Comprehensive evaluation of Plan Sierra's activities during the period ca. 1979-84.
  Developing Countries Program/Rural Poverty and Resources; Developing Countries Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  08450199
  Plan Sierra
  Rural development projects -- Dominican Republic; Agricultural development projects -- Dominican Republic
- Entrepreneurial Research Project: Working papers and a project proposal (Reports 011412), 1969 (Box 474)
  Appendix includes working papers for the seminar by the following authors: Kamini Adhikari, Sabyasachi Bhattacharya, Wayne Broehl, Dool Singh, Jitendra Singh, and Dwijendra Tripathi. Selected bibliography on the Indian business and entrepreneurial systems
  06990299
  144 leaves.
  Entrepreneurial function and its locus; Approaches to entrepreneuship; Entrepreneurship in the less developed world; A note on field work of research; Framework for the study of institution building and the management of innovation in a developing country; Ind
  Seminar on entrepreneurship (1969 April 22-June 15: Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH)
  Business enterprises, Foreign -- Developing countries; Business enterprises, Foreign -- India; Self-employed -- Developing countries; Self-employed -- India; Entrepreneurship
- Report on research awards in the disciplines of economics, politics and social science and under the conflict programme for the period 1974-1987, 1988 Feb. (Reports 011413) (Box 474)
  Includes a schedule of research awards made between 1974 and 1982.
  07300415
  22 p.; 34 leaves.
  Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Social sciences -- Research -- Ireland; Research grants -- Ireland
- Border flows and economic interdependence in California/Baja California urban areas: submitted to the Office of Policy Development and Research, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (Reports 011414), 1981 (Box 474)
  National Affairs/Office of the Vice President; International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean
  07850651
  [1], x, 113 leaves.
  Economic forecasting -- Mexico -- Baja (Calif.); Economic forecasting -- Imperial Valley (Calif. and Mexico); Econometric models -- Mexico -- Baja (Calif.); Econometric models -- Imperial Valley (Calif. and Mexico)
- The CBARC input-output model of Imperial Valley: including an economic impact analytical procedures manual, July 31 (Reports 011415), 1981 (Box 475)
  [1], v, 54 leaves.
- Community service programs in independent schools (Reports 011416), 1986 (Box 475)
  08500813
  124 p. -- 28 cm.
  Youth -- Employment -- United States; Private schools -- United States; Social service -- United States -- Citizen participation; Student volunteers in social service -- United States; Community and school -- United States
- The role of remedial education in improving school achievement, job training and future employment draft (Reports 011417), 1983 (Box 475)
  88 leaves.
  Basic education -- United States; Computer-assisted instruction; Youth -- Employment -- United States; High school dropouts; Economic development -- Effect of education on -- United States; Labor supply -- Effect of education on; Literacy -- United States
- Papers on education and economics in Latin America, 1976 (Reports 011418), 1977
  ECIEL research on education and economics from the Catholic University of Chile's Interdisciplinary Program of Research in Education (PIIE), Paraguayan Center of Sociological Studies (CPES & CEPADES), and the Center of Educational Studies, of the Secretar
  7400653
  various pagings; 28 cm.
  Education -- Economic aspects -- Latin America; Labor supply -- Effect of education on -- Latin America; Latin America -- Economic conditions -- 1945
- Educacion y mercado de trabajo en el sector moderno de la economia urbana: Plan de analisis (Reports 011418-001), 1976 (Box 475)
  Latin America and the Caribbean
  07400653
  Programa De Estudos Conjuntos Sobre Integracao Economica Da America Latina
  Education -- Economic aspects -- Latin America; Labor supply -- Effect of education on -- Latin America
- Dejamos constancia de la efieciente colaboracino del Programa Interdisciplinario de Investigaciones en Educacion de la Universidad Catolica de Chile (PIIE) (Reports 011418-002), 1976 (Box 475)
- Determinantes del Rendimiento Educativo en el Paraguay (Reports 011418-003), 1977 (Box 475)
- Ensayos ECIEL ECIEL essays, and related papers (Reports 011419), 1977
  Research on education, labor markets and economic integration from the Catholic University of Chile's Interdisciplinary Program of Research in Education (PIIE), the Center of Educational Studies, of the Secretariat of Public Education, Mexico (CEE), and t
  Education -- Economic aspects -- Latin America; Labor supply -- Effect of education on -- Latin America; Latin America -- Economic integration; Latin America -- Economic conditions -- 1945
- Ensayos ECIEL, no. 3, Agosto (Reports 011419-001), 1976 (Box 475)
- Papel de la educacion en le sector "Tradicional urbano" de la economia (Reports 011419-002), 1977 (Box 475)
- Un enfoque integrativo para el estudio de la dinamica del mercado de trabajo (Reports 011419-003), 1977 (Box 475)
- Proyecto educacion y mercado del trabajo en el sector moderno de la economia /Fernando Tagle. (Reports 011419-004), 1976 (Box 475)
- Educacion y mercado de trabajo urbano en Colombia: una comparacion entre sectores moderno y no modernos: Resultados de un estudio piloto (Reports 011419-005), 1978 (Box 475)
- Resumen del Seminario del Programa de Estudios Conjuntos sobre Integracion Economica Latinoamericana (1975-1984), Volume I (Reports 011420-001) (Box 476)
  v.; 28 cm.
  Programa de Estudios Conjuntos sobre Integracion Economica Latinoamericana. Seminario.
  Education -- Economic aspects -- Latin America
- Resumen del Seminario del Programa de Estudios Conjuntos sobre Integracion Economica Latinoamericana (1975-1984), Volume II (Reports 011420-002), undated
- Papers on costs of education and economic development in Latin America, 1976 (Reports 011421), 1978 (Box 476)
  ECIEL research papers from the project on Costs and Determining factors in Education in Latin America.
  various pagings; 18-28 cm.
- Papers on education and employment in Latin America, 1973 (Reports 011422), 1976
  ECIEL research papers from the Catholic University of Ecuador's Institute of Economic Research (IIE), the Catholic University of Chile's Interdisciplinary Program of Research in Education (PIIE), the Brazilian School of Public Administration (EBAP/FGV) an
  various pagings; 34 cm.
- Determinantes de escolarizacao (Reports 011422-001), 1976 (Box 476)
- Los determinantes de la escolaridad en el Ecuador (Reports 011422-002), 1976 (Box 476)
- Dos anos de labor (Reports 011422-003), 1976 (Box 476)
- Education, earnings and occupational mobility in Salvador, Brazil (Reports 011422-004), 1975 (Box 476)
- Educacion y mercado del trabajo en el sector moderno (un estudio de casos): Resumen (Reports 011422-005), 1978 (Box 476)
- Estado de avance proyecto: Educacion y mercado del trabajo en le sector moderno (Reports 011422-006), undated (Box 477)
- Educacion y productividad en el area rural, Documento de trabajo no. 1 (Reports 011422-007), 1975 (Box 477)
- Educacion y productividad en el area rural, Documento de trabajo no. 1 (Reports 011422-008), undated (Box 477)
- Plan operativo para el analisis e los costos en el nivel primario (Reports 011422-009), undated (Box 477)
- Estudio de costos en el nivel primario Ecuador (Reports 011422-010), undated (Box 477)
- Estratificacao Social e Educacao: Caminhos e Alternativas para o Homem do Campo (Reports 011422-011), 1976 (Box 477)
- A test market design for the introduction of oral rehydration salts in Bangladesh (Reports 011424), 1981 (Box 477)
  Antidiarrheals -- Testing; Oral medication -- Bangladesh; Antidiarrheals -- Marketing; Diarrhea -- Bangladesh
- Some issues of franchising cable television systems in the Dayton metropolitan area: Working note, 1971 Nov. (Reports 011425) (Box 477)
  Cable television -- Ohio -- Dayton -- Access
- Papers on language and linguistic study, 1965-1980. (Reports 011426)
  Contains reports removed from the Attachments section of a grant to the Center for Applied Linguistics including monographs, conference proceedings, newsletters, bibliographies of linguistic publications, and educational material.
  6500372
  Applied linguistics; Language and education; Education, Bilingual -- United States; Language and languages -- Study and teaching; Language and languages -- Ability testing; Reading; Black English; Indians of North America -- Languages; Indians of North America
- Five interrelated studies to increase the effectiveness of English language instruction in schools: BALA Final Report, Volume 1, Section 1 (Reports 011426-001), 1971 (Box 477)
  Education and Public Policy
  06500372
  Center for Applied Linguistics grant attachments
  Applied linguistics; Language and education; Education, Bilingual -- United States; Language and languages -- Study and teaching
- Five interrelated studies to increase the effectiveness of English language instruction in schools: BALA Final Report, Volume 2, Sections 2-51 (Reports 011426-002), 1971 (Box 478)
- Five interrelated studies to increase the effectiveness of English language instruction in schools: BALA Project: Progress report (Reports 011426-003), 1970 (Box 478)
- Recommendations concerning language needs of Vietnamese refugees (Reports 011426-004), 1975 (Box 478)
- Interdisciplinary committee on reading problems (Reports 011426-005), 1971 (Box 478)
- Indochinese refugee education guides, no. 3-13 (Reports 011426-006), undated (Box 479)
- Indochinese refugee education guides, no. 1-7 (Reports 011426-007), undated (Box 479)
- A Personnel Resources Directory for the Education of Indochinese Refugees: Supplement 2 (Reports 011426-008), 1975 (Box 479)
- Vietnamese Refugee Alert Bulletin: no. 1 (Reports 011426-009), 1975 (Box 479)
- Indochinese Refugee Alert Bulletin, no. 1-10 (Reports 011426-010), 1975-1978 (Box 479)
- Correspondence re: Center for Applied Linguistics publications (Reports 011426-011), 1975 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 3 (Reports 011426-012), 1966 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 5 (Reports 011426-013), 1967 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 8 (Reports 011426-014), 1969 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 9 (Reports 011426-015), 1969 (Box 479)
- Linguistics in the 1970s (Reports 011426-016) (Box 479)
- Styles of learning among American Indians: An outline for research: Report and recommendations of a conference held at Stanford University, August 8-10 (Reports 011426-017), 1969 (Box 479)
- Planning conference for a bilingual kindergarten program for Navajo children: Conclusions and recommendations, October 11-12 (Reports 011426-018), 1968 (Box 479)
- Colloque International sur les Problems des langues secondes (Reports 011426-019), 1966 (Box 479)
- Second national conference of EPDA bilingual education project directors: Preparation and certification of teachers of Bilingual-Bicultural Education, Albuquerque, New Mexico, February 13-15 (Reports 011426-020), 1975 (Box 479)
- Conference proceedings, with a paper on Sociolinguistic Surveys: State of the Art. International conference on the methodology of sociolinguistic surveys, Montreal, Quebec, Canada, May 19-21 (Reports 011426-021), 1975 (Box 479)
- A survey of the current study and reaching of North American Indian languages in the United States and Canada (Reports 011426-022), 1975 (Box 479)
- Recommendations of language policy in Indian education (Reports 011426-023), 1973 (Box 479)
- Inventory of projects and activities in reading and English, no. 1-4 (Reports 011426-024), 1966 (Box 480)
- Selected list of instructional materials for English as a second language: Audio-Visual aids (Reports 011426-025), 1974 (Box 480)
- Guidelines for the preparation and certification of teachers of bilingual/bicultural education (Reports 011426-026), 1974 (Box 480)
- Teachers of English to speakers of other languages: Report to NACTEFL, October 24 (Reports 011426-027), 1975 (Box 480)
- National Advisory Council on the Teaching of English as a Foreign Language: Decisions of Meeting, no.6 (Reports 011426-028), 1965 (Box 480)
- TOEFL: Testing of English as a foreign language (Reports 011426-029), 1965 (Box 480)
  Applied linguistics; Language and education; Education, Bilingual -- United States; Language and languages -- Study and teaching; Center for Applied Linguistics
- The relationship between TESOL and the Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-030), 1972 (Box 480)
- Teaching English to speakers of other languages: United States activities: 1967 (Reports 011426-031), 1968 (Box 480)
- Report on Center for Applied Linguistics international activities (Reports 011426-032), undated (Box 480)
- Language in Education Committee: Preliminary report (Reports 011426-033), 1969 (Box 480)
- John Lotz: a personal memoir (Reports 011426-034), undated (Box 480)
- On social, regional, and age variation in black English (Reports 011426-035), 1974 (Box 480)
- One view of continuing functions in English language education a the Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-036), undated (Box 480)
- Strengthening UCLA's training, research, and service resources in the teaching of English as a second language (Reports 011426-037), 1973 (Box 480)
- Retrospective survey: The University of the West Indies (Reports 011426-038), undated (Box 480)
- The Indian language assistance project (Reports 011426-039), 1978 (Box 480)
- Language policy for Indian education (Reports 011426-040), 1973 (Box 480)
- The Sudan: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-041), 1975 (Box 480)
- Indonesia: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-042), 1975 (Box 480)
- Ethiopia: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-043), 1975 (Box 480)
- Peru: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-044), 1975 (Box 480)
- Income, expenditures and general fund projections: Fiscal Year 1972 (Reports 011426-045), 1972-1973 (Box 480)
- Center for Applied Linguistics Annual Report (Reports 011426-046), 1970 (Box 481)
- Progress report on CAL contribution to NCBE operation (Reports 011426-047), 1978 (Box 481)
- Report to the Board of Trustees - December 1973 and (Reports 011426-048), 1973-1974 (Box 481)
- Center for Applied Linguistics: Report on examinations with supplementary information, years ended September 30, 1978 and (Reports 011426-049) (Box 481)
- News clippings and misc. reports, correspondence, etc. re: Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-050), 1974-1975 (Box 481)
- Ownership alternatives for cable television in the Dayton metropolitan area: Working note, 1971 Nov. (Reports 011427) (Box 481)
- State-tribal relations: handbook (Reports 011428), 1981 (Box 481)
  "This material is based upon work supported by the Department of Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, under BIA Grant Number K51C1420G030, Ford Foundation and Donner Foundation." -t.p./cover page
  08150145
  Indians of North America -- Government relations; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- Instructional uses of cable television in Washington, D.C.: draft, 1971 (Reports 011429) (Box 481)
  37 leaves.
  Cable television -- Washington (D.C.); Educational television stations -- Washington (D.C.)
- Attachments, 1977-80. (Reports 011430)
  Research reports, bibliographies and conference proceedings. This is not a complete collection of ATRCW papers.
  7600464
  1 archives box (5 linear inches containing 9 items).
  Rural women -- Africa; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Employment -- Liberia; Fisheries -- Liberia; Women -- Employment -- Ghana; Women -- Employment -- Kenya; Women -- Employment -- Zambia; Children -- Zambia -- Mortality; Infants -- Zambia
- Women Workers in Ghana, Kenya, Zambia: A Comparative Analysis of Women's Employment in the Modern Wage Sector (Reports 011430-001), 1979 (Box 481)
  07600464
  Rural women -- Africa; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Employment -- Africa
- Broadcasting for the Integration of Women in Development: The ATRCW Perspective (Reports 011430-002), 1977 (Box 481)
- Report of the Second Regional Conference on the Integration of Women in Development, Lusaka, Zambia, 3-7 (Reports 011430-003), 1979 (Box 481)
- Programs for Better Family Living Component, in the United Nations Economic Commission for Africa and Research Centre for Women (ATRCW) of the Social Development Division (Reports 011430-004), 1978 (Box 481)
- Report of the Review Mission, African Training and Research Centre for Women (Reports 011430-005), 1978 (Box 481)
- Women and Development in Africa: An Annotated Bibliography (Reports 011430-006), 1977 (Box 481)
- Law and the Status of Women in Nigeria (Reports 011430-007), 1979 (Box 482)
- Interrelationships among Infant and Childhood Mortality, Socio-economic Factors and Fertility in Zambia: A Case Study of Lusaka and Keembe (Reports 011430-008), undated (Box 482)
- Women and the Fishing Industry in Liberia (Reports 011430-009), 1979 (Box 482)
- Report of the Seminar on Rural Development and Women's Employment Problems in Kenya (1981 November 16-21: Nairobi, Kenya) (Reports 011431), 1983 (Box 482)
  08250361
  118 leaves.
  Seminar on Rural Development and Women's Employment Problems in Kenya (1981 November 16-21: Nairobi, Kenya)
  Women -- Employment -- Kenya; Women in rural development -- Kenya; Unemployment -- Kenya; Underemployment -- Kenya; Migration, Internal -- Kenya; Sociology, Rural -- Kenya
- Establishment of planning cells in certain DPAP districts: report of an action research project (Reports 011432), 1983 (Box 482)
  07700190
  41 leaves, 166 pages.
  Regional planning -- India
- An evaluation study of the operations of Rural Development Cell (Reports 011433), 1982 (Box 482)
  07700090
  [3], 61 leaves.
  Rural development projects -- India
- Management education for development: comparative experience in Malaysia, the Philippines, and Thailand (Reports 011434), 1976 (Box 482)
  07300090; 06300106
  iv, 370 leaves, tables -- 28 cm.
  Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Malaysia; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Southeast Asia; Education and state
- Developing a program of public information as graduate education: annual report to the Ford Foundation 1978-1979 1979? (Reports 011435) (Box 483)
  Report covers first year of operations of a three-year project.
  07800402
  101 leaves.
  Education -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Education -- Graduate work; Moral education; Competency-based educational tests; Basic education
- Final report to the Ford Foundation: grant no. 825-0804 May 15, 1982--May 15, 1983 1984? (Reports 011436) (Box 483)
  Includes 15 photographs.
  08250804
  14 leaves.
  Housing development -- Georgia -- Savannah (Ga.); Housing rehabilitation -- Georgia -- Savannah (Ga.)
- Implementation of affirmative action: a preliminary identification of impetus and enabling factors (Reports 011437), 1979 (Box 483)
  07390804
  18 pages.
  Affirmative action programs -- Virginia -- Arlington
- Computing activities in selected institutions in Indonesia: A report of a consulting trip to Indonesia commissioned by the Ford Foundation (Reports 011438), 1975 (Box 483)
  07290255
  v, 127 leaves.
  Computation laboratories -- Indonesia; Computer engineering -- Indonesia; Computers -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia
- The Arts Income Management System: program summary (Reports 011439), 1985 (Box 483)
  08100509
  v, 148 pages.
  Microcomputers and the arts; Arts -- Management
- Proposal for Arts Income Management System (Reports 011440), 1981 (Box 483)
- Arts Income Management System: system specifications, July 10 (Reports 011441), 1980 (Box 483)
  111, 61, [13] leaves.
- Education and employment: Easing the transition from school to work (Reports 011442), 1982 (Box 483, Reel R-9302)
  Includes 6 appendices.
  Vocational education -- United States; Labor supply -- Effect of education on; Youth -- Employment -- Law and legislation -- United States; Unemployment -- United States
- Work, service, and learning: Overcoming deficits with opportunities 198 (Reports 011443), 1982 (Box 483)
  Reviews the accomplishments of two grantees: the Remediation and Training Institute and Public/Private Ventures.
  Poor youth -- Employment -- United States; Poor youth -- Services for -- United States; Socially handicapped youth -- Services for -- United States; Basic education -- United States; Remedial teaching -- United States; Labor supply -- United States
- Cutting through 1986? (Reports 011444) (Box 483)
  Basic education; Competency-based education; Labor supply -- Effect of education on; Youth -- Employment -- United States; Minority youth; Illegitimacy -- United States
- The "trainee business" phenomenon: Current operations, prospects, and recommendations for Ford Foundation involvement (Reports 011445), 1983 (Box 483)
  Reviews four trainee businesses: San Francisco Renaissance, Court Employment Project, Advocap, and Freedom Factory. Includes letter from the author to Gordon Berlin and Ellen Potash [Arrick], for whom this report was prepared.
  30, ii leaves.
  Occupational training -- United States; Employees -- Training of -- United States; Manpower policy -- United States; Youth -- Employment -- United States; Small business -- United States
- Site visits to urban poverty programs for youth work, service and learning, January 30, 1986. (Reports 011446) (Box 483)
  All sites were in New York City. Includes: essays and supporting documents describing the sites visited.
  Youth -- Employment -- United States; Labor supply -- United States -- Effect of education on; Basic education; Labor service -- United States
- Getting credit where credit is due: community development credit unions and the economics of self-help (Reports 011447), 1987 (Box 483)
  60 leaves.
  Community development, Urban -- United States; Credit unions; Small business -- Finance
- Employment and income generation, plant closings and worker ownership: The case for a Foundation role 198 (Reports 011448), 1984 (Box 483)
  Concerned in large part with the activities of Philadelphia Association for Cooperative Enterprise (PACE) and Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA). Includes two appendices; newspaper clippings.
  31 leaves.
  Employee ownership -- United States; Plant shutdowns -- United States; Occupations -- United States; New business enterprises -- United States
- An assessment of program related investments use of social financial intermediaries, 1981 Aug. (Reports 011449) (Box 483)
  Evaluates the activities of five intermediary organizations. Includes: 4-part Appendix entitled "Investing in Financial Intermediaries--a Concept Paper for the Ford Foundation" and a bibliography.